

stodyshev@gmail.com |

sergeyt |

sergey.todyshev |

sergey.

Summary_

Current Software Engineer at Xored. 15 years of experience specializing in any kind of software development. I like writing efficient code, solving challenging tasks, learning new technologies and tools. I have two beautiful kids and two funny cats.

Work Experience _

Xored Novosibirsk, Russia

TECHNICAL LEADER

- Jan. 2016 PRESENT • Integration of B2B web apps for the communications industry to the private Cloud. Using JavaScript, Java, RESTful Web Services, Go, Docker.
- Development of Spirent Velocity platform. Linux, Java, Go, React, Redux.

GrapeCity Novosibirsk, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2011 - Jan. 2016

- Development of GrapeCity ActiveReports & ActiveReports Server components.
- · Made a significant contribution rewriting report engine to dramatically boost performance. This is reflected in latest releases of Active Reports.

CodeFibers Berdsk, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2009 - 2010

· Principal engineer of CarbonDocs - fast HTML rendering engine with parallel pipeline with ASP.NET-like template system capable to generate PDF, Image documents.

Data Dynamics Novosibirsk, Russia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2007 - 2009

2003 - 2004

2002 - 2004

- · Principal author of cross-compiler (binary translator) from .NET bytecode to Adobe Flash Player bytecode. Since 2009 the compiler is used to translate Active Reports Flash Viewer assembly into SWF file runnable in Adobe Flash Player. Unfortunately the compiler is not maintained since 2009, but it is very stable (covered with thousands of tests) and still running on build machines to compile Flash Viewer.
- Development of Data Dynamics Reports components

DIOPTIC GmbH Novosibirsk, Russia

FREELANCER

Development of voXcat - tomography analysis software

CadWise

Novosibirsk, Russia

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER • Development of AutoCAD runtime extensions like Power Studio

- Development of Data Access Layer to query and store data in Microsoft Access Database
- Development of shared UI components for embedded databases used in all company products

Institute of Automation and Electrometry

Novosibirsk, Russia

STUDENT

2002 - 2007

- Development of Device Manager hardware abstraction layer to control multiple devices of unique Circle Laser Writing System created by IAE
- Abstract Control System allows drawing visual programs to control real devices something similar to LabVIEW
- Integration of CPython scripting to CLWS software
- · Development of software for phase-shifting interferometers and profilometer

Education

Novosibirsk State University

Novosibirsk, Russia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 1999 - June. 2004

Institute of Automation and Electrometry

Novosibirsk, Russia

PHD STUDENT

Sep. 2004 - June. 2007